erat (he/she/it/there) was tam so homo man, human in +  acc into, onto terra land, earth, ground igitur therefore in +  abl in, on est (he/she/it/there) is ingens huge ut  + subj (so) that, (in order) to me me iterum again eum ;  eam him, it; her, it festino I hurry iuvenis young (man) ad to, towards, at a, ab (away) from mors death qui,  quae who, which annus year nam for deus god cum +  abl with necesse necessary non not iter journey omnis all, every ille ,  ill a ,  illud he, she, it; that (those) laetus happy pauci a few et and mox soon quam than , whom, which, how quod because, which navis ship si if multus much, many perterritus terrified unus one sed but puella girl verbum word hic, haec, hoc this (these) rex king vix hardly, scarcely dea goddess silva wood noli ( te ) donÆt ei to/for him, her, it  urbs city discedo I leave video;  vidi I see; I saw neco I kill discessi I left esse (t) to be, he/she/it was navigo I sail teneo I hold conspexi I noticed aperio I open amo I love facio ;  feci I make, do; I made, did apertus (having been) opened effugio I escape rogo I ask cupio I want libero I free tu ,  te you (sg) puto I think peto I seek, beg, ask, attack ubi when, where cibus food quaero I search, ask (for) vir man comes companion cogo I force habeo I have facilis easy coactus (having been) forced inquit he/she says, said femina woman appareo I appear e, ex from, out of fortis brave, strong appropinquo I approach per through suus his, her, its, their clamo I shout -que and tantus so great, such a great impero I order tamen however dormio I sleep pono I put, place uxor wife audio I hear, listen posui I put, placed eius his, her,  its ; of him, her, it duco I lead oppugno I attack posse(t) to be able, he/she/it was able occido I kill amicus friend caput head advenio I arrive cur why pulcher beautiful iussi I ordered dirus dreadful se him-, her-, it(self); them(selves) persuadeo I persuade dum while simulac as soon as cognosco I get to know, find out dux leader dico ;  dixi I  say;  I said cognovi I got to know, found out etiam even, also volo I want conatur he/she tries filia daughter cum + subj when, since alius other, another gladius sword equus horse domum (to) home insula island, block of flats iratus angry iam now, already maritus husband postquam after ibi there nihil nothing statim at once, immediately manus hand, group nunc now tandem finally, at last regina queen porta gate redire (t) to return, (s)he was returning eos ,  eas them prope near rediit he/she returned habito I live quo modo how deinde then oro I beg solus alone, lonely ego I accepi I accepted, received subito suddenly enim for consilium cepi I had an idea tristis sad filius son constituo I decide tum then miles soldier relinquo I leave behind vultus face, expression pater father ceteri the rest mihi to/for me quamquam although donum gift coepi I begin Notes for teachers: IÆve included the top 150( ish ) most frequent words, including some additional inflected forms  where some forms are more common than others. They are ordered by frequency ( erat  appears 68 times over the 8 papers, while  coepi  appears only 4 times) Everything up to and including  cupio appears  on average  at least once per paper (caveat that some words (esp. nouns but not limited to them) might appear lots on one paper but not on the next. Beyond that, the number of iterations drop quite quickly: everything from  cogo  onwards appears  on average  once every other paper!
